<resources>
    <string name="app_name">EBM Stats Calc</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="mainScreenAlertTitle">Welcome</string>
    <string name="mainScreenAlertMessage">EBM Stats Calc helps clinicians and educators do clinical reasoning a little bit easier and more effectively
    by helping you \'do the math\' that everyone hates. The app will (1) calculate NNT\'s from event rates, (2) calculate Post-test Probability from Sensitivity,
    Specificity, LR+ and LR-, and (3) demonstrate diagnostic principles to learners dynamically.</string>
    <string name="mainScreenAlertBtnName">Get Started</string>


    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_disclaimer">Disclaimer</string>
    <string name="title_aboutApp">About App</string>
    <string name="title_ref">References</string>
    <string name="title_moreApps">More Apps</string>

    <string name="actionbar_HomeScreen">EBM Stats Calculators</string>
    <string name="actionbar_NNTScreen">Number Needed to Treat</string>
    <string name="actionbar_MoreInfoNNT">about NNT</string>
    <string name="actionbar_PostTestScreens">Diagnosis</string>
    <string name="actionbar_MoreInfoPostTest">about Diagnosis</string>

    <string name="home_screen_heading">Choose a calculator you wish to use</string>
    <string name="home_screen_button1">NNT from Rates or Events</string>
    <string name="home_screen_button2">Post-test Prob via Sens &amp; Spec</string>
    <string name="home_screen_button3">Post-test Prob via Likelihood Ratios</string>

    <string name="home_screen_belowButton1">Number Need to Treat (or harm or screen)</string>
    <string name="home_screen_belowButton2">Supply pre-test probability, Sens, Spec</string>
    <string name="home_screen_belowButton3">Supply pre-test probability, LR+, LR-</string>


    <string name="disclaimerScreen_text">Dear Colleague,
        \n\nI have two general purposes for offering these calculators. First is to help you think a bit more quantitatively about the
         medical care that you provide.
        Second is to help you illustrate points more effectively to students and residents about quantitative matters such as \"just how impactful is
        this treatment\" via NNT or \"just how certain of this diagnosis are we\" with posttest probabilities.
        \n\nThe authors of the app have tried to faithfully present calculators and explanations while not substituting our own judgment.
        If you think we have erred in presentation or explanation, please let us know!
        \n\nThis app is no substitute for knowledge and experience doing the quantitative reasoning of diagnosis and treatment in patient care.
        The app does not make medical decisions for you on diagnosis or treatment, it just helps you think quantitatively, helping you with the math.
        The app is merely a quick reference and tool for material you already know.</string>

    <string name="aboutAppScreen_heading">Development of EBM Stats Calc App</string>
    <string name="aboutAppScreen_text">Written to put basic yet dynamic tools for quantitative reasoning in diagnosis and treatment in the hands of clinicians,
        students, residents, and especially educators at the point of care.
        \n\nCONTENT:  Joshua Steinberg MD, UHS Wilson Family Medicine Residency, Binghamton NY, and Daniel Kaufman MS-3,
        SUNY Upstate Medical University, Binghamton Clinical Campus.
        \n\nDESIGN:  Joshua Steinberg MD (all me, no one else to blame).
        \n\nPROGRAMMING: Harshad Loya, MS Computer Science, Binghamton University, SUNY.
        \n\nVersion: 1.1    Build 1
        \n\nCopyright: June, 2018
        \n\nFeedback: jds.pocapps@gmail.com</string>

    <string name="dashboard_name">Joshua Steinberg MD</string>
    <string name="dashboard_email">jds.pocapps@gmail.com</string>

    <string name="refScreen_heading">References and Internet Links</string>
    <string name="refScreen_text">
        \n<a href="https://books.google.com/books/about/Evidence_based_Medicine.html?id=oIJrAAAAMAAJ">Evidence-Based Medicine, How to Practice
            and Teach EBM, 2nd Ed. Sackett DL, et. al., Churchhill Livingstone, Edinburgh, 2000.</a>
        \n\n\n<a href="http://www.cebm.net/blog/2014/02/03/likelihood-ratios/">Center for Evidence Based Medicine, Oxford University,
         Likelihood Ratios discussion, accessed Jan. 2, 2018.</a>
        \n\n\n<a href="http://www.thennt.com/home-lr/">Examples of Likelihood Ratios (LR+ and LR-) from across the breadth of medicine at www.TheNNT.com
         (and they have plenty of NNT\'s too).</a>
    </string>

    <!-- More Apps Screen Texts -->
    <string name="moreAppsScreen_title">"More apps for clinicians\nby Joshua Steinberg MD"</string>
    <string name="moreAppsScreen_text">"I keep a list of apps* written by anyone (mostly others) which I recommend for clinicians, nurses, residents, and students serving many fields of medicine, especially my home of full-spectrum family medicine. A copy is always online here."</string>
    <string name="moreAppsScreen_button">"More Apps List"</string>
    <string name="moreAppsScreen_button2">"My Other Play Store Apps"</string>
    <string name="moreAppsScreen_text2">"* I have no financial relationship or financial benefit from any of these apps, even my own."</string>

    <!-- Post-test Probability via Sensitivity and Specificity Calculator Screen-->
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_PopuVal1">100</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_PopuVal2">1,000</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_PopuVal3">10,000</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl1">Population</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl2">Pre-test Probability as %</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl3">Sensitivity as %</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl4">Specificity as %</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl5">Disease</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl6">Pos</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl7">Neg</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl8">Test Pos</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl9">Test Neg</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl10">Pos Predictive Value as %</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl11">Neg Predictive Value as %</string>
    <string name="SensSpecCalcScreen_Lbl12">Post-test Probability</string>

    <!-- Default/Initial Values for fields -->
    <string name="DefaultValue_0.00">0.00</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_0">0</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_0percent">0%</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_0.5">0.5</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_1.00">1.00</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_1.0">1.0</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_2.0">2.0</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_10">10</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_10.0">10.0</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_25percent">25%</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_40.0">40.0</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_50percent">50%</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_75percent">75%</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_90.0">90.0</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_100">100</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_100percent">100%</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_TrueP">TrueP</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_FalseP">FalseP</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_TrueN">TrueN</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_FalseN">FalseN</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_TestP">TestP</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_TestN">TestN</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_DzP">DzP</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_DzN">DzN</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_Total">Total</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_PPV">PPV</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_NPV">NPV</string>
    <string name="DefaultValue_Prob">prob</string>

    <string name="nnt_preference_file_key">EBMStatsCalc_NNT_SharedPreferences</string>
    <string name="sensspec_preference_file_key">EBMStatsCalc_SensSpec_SharedPreferences</string>
    <string name="likelihood_preference_file_key">EBMStatsCalc_Likelihood_SharedPreferences</string>

    <!--<string name="accountSelectionCancelledToast">"Default Name, Image and Email Id will be shown in Dashboard"</string>-->

    <string name="moreInfoButton">ⓘ more info</string>

    <!-- Post-test Probability via Likelihood Ratios Calculator Screen-->
    <string name="LikelihoodScreen_Lbl2">Likelihood Ratio POS</string>
    <string name="LikelihoodScreen_Lbl3">Likelihood Ratio NEG</string>
    <string name="LikelihoodScreen_Lbl4">Post-test Probability as %</string>
    <string name="LikelihoodScreen_Lbl5">Test Positive</string>
    <string name="LikelihoodScreen_Lbl6">Test Negative</string>

    <!-- NNT Calculator Screen-->
    <string name="nntScreen_label1">Two Rates</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label2">enter two rates between 0.00 and 1.00</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label3">Rate1</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label4">Rate2</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label6">Two Percentages</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label7">enter two percentages between 0 and 100</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label8">%age1</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label9">%age2</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label11">Numbers of events and patients</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label12">enter event totals and patient totals</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label13">Events1</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label14">Events2</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label16">Patients1</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_label17">Patients2</string>

    <string name="nntScreen_eqLabel1">NNT = 1 / (</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_eqLabel2">-</string>
    <string name="nntScreen_eqLabel3">) = </string>
    <string name="nntScreen_eqLabel4">-----</string>

    <string name="nntScreen_commonLabel">NNT</string>


    <!-- NNT More Info Screen-->
    <string name="nnt_moreInfo_text">Number Needed to Treat (NNT) is a way of quantifying the effectiveness of a given intervention.
        A study comparing Treatment A to Treatment B might show A statistically significantly superior via a p-value or a 95% confidence interval.
        But is the statistically significantly superior treatment also clinically significantly superior?  NNT is a great way to estimate the magnitude of
        benefit, and quantify how much better one approach is compared to an alternative.  NNT is how many patients must be treated with Treatment A
        rather than Treatment B (or placebo or no treatment at all) in order to change one patient\'s outcome.
        \n\nFor example, let\'s say a study reports on two randomized groups of 100 people each, one group taking a statin medication, the other taking placebo.
        \n\nOver perhaps 5 years of treatment, 10 patients in the placebo control group have a heart attack, yielding a risk in the control group is 10/100, or 10%.
        In the statin group, just 7 heart attacks occur, for an risk of 7/100, or 7%.  The statin didn\'t stop every heart attack as 7 still occurred.
        And most patients didn\'t benefit from the statin, as 90 had no heart attack regardless of treatment.
        But 3 outcomes were changed – 3 heart attacks were prevented by taking statin rather than placebo. It took 100 patients treated with
        statin rather than placebo to save these 3 heart attacks. So it took appx. 33 patients treated in order to save every 1 heart attack. \nNNT of 33.
        \n\nThe formula for NNT is the inverse of the absolute risk reduction, or...
        \n\nNNT = 1 ÷ (Risk1 – Risk2)
        \n\nNNT can be used to quantify the magnitude of benefit for any intervention, including standard things like a medication or surgery, and also for
        entire intervention programs like a screening program.</string>

    <!-- Sens Spec and Likelihood More Info Screen-->
    <string name="postTest_moreInfo_text">Why do we physicians use diagnostic tests?  Because we want to wind up more convinced about whether a
        patient has a disease.  Let\'s say you think to yourself, \“hmmm, I think the chance this child has Strep Throat is appx 40%, but I\'d like to be more
        convinced one way or the other.\”  We start out with a certain level of suspicion and hope that a positive diagnostic test will move our suspicion of
        the disease upwards much closer to certainty, and likewise we hope that a negative diagnostic test will move our suspicion downwards also towards
        certainty.  Usually we do this kind of thinking in our heads in a qualitative way.  On occasion, you may wish to be quantitative, do the math, and
        consider the numbers. That may be why you have this app. Here is a brief educational review of terms and concepts.

        \n\nSensitivity is the ability of a test to correctly identify disease in a population who has the disease. For example, if you have 100 patients with
        the STD chlamydia and your test can find it in 94 of them and miss it in 6, the sensitivity is 94%, or...

        \n\nSens  = TruePositives ÷ (TruePositives + FalseNegatives)

        \n\nA highly sensitive test will identify nearly everyone with the disease, which sounds good, but it may also label patients without the disease as
        having the disease, too, which brings us to Specificity.

        \n\nSpecificity is the ability of a test to correctly identify not having a disease in a population which does not have the disease. Using the same
        kind of example as above, if you have 100 patients who do not have the STD chlamydia and your test can correctly identify 97 of them as not having
        the disease and mislabel only 3 as having it, the specificity is 97%, or...

        \n\nSpec  = TrueNegatives ÷ (TrueNegatives + FalsePositives)

        \n\nA highly specific test will correctly identify everyone without the disease, but it may miss patients who do have the disease, which is why the
        property Sensitivity is important, too.

        \n\nThe problem for clinicians, however, is that we never run tests on 100 patients whom we know to have a disease nor do we run tests on
        100 patients whom we know not to have a disease.  We start with patients, or more likely a single patient, who may or may not have a disease, and
        we hope a test can move us from uncertainty towards enough certainty to let us get on with treating the patient with some confidence that we\'re
        doing the right thing.

        \n\nA physician\'s initial impression of the chance of disease is called the Pretest Probability.  This initial level of suspicion could come from
        careful history and physical or perhaps it could come from baseline rates of a disease in a population (prevalence).  The calculator in this app
        shows you a 2x2 table starting with a pretest probability (which you can enter as a number or via the slider), a population size (100, 1000, or 10,000
        to make the numbers big easy and round), and sensitivity and specificity you enter. The 2x2 table shows you how many total people will test
        positive, and of those, how many will also have the disease. This is positive predictive value (PPV), or the chance that a positive test is likely
        to be true.

        \n\nPPV  = TruePositives ÷ TotalPositives

        \n\nFor a positive test, PPV is the post-test probability, or the suspicion of disease after a test has been performed.

        \n\nIf the test result is negative, then one can also see how likely a negative result is to be true.  This is the negative predictive value (NPV).

        \n\nNPV  = TrueNegatives ÷ TotalNegatives

        \n\nThe post-test probability of disease after a negative test is 1 – NPV.

        \n\nThe Likelihood Ratio (LR) is another way of expressing how a diagnostic test influences physician impression of the probability of disease.  It
        is defined as the likelihood that a given test result would be expected in a patient with the target disorder compared to the likelihood that that
        same result would be expected in a patient without the target disorder.  This is so abstract and confusing as to warrant restatement with helpful
        annotation!  The likelihood ratio is defined as the likelihood that a given test result would be expected in a patient with the target disorder [one
        likelihood] compared to [ratio] the likelihood that that same result would be expected in a patient without the target disorder [another
        likelihood].  This can expressed for positive and negative test results, using the terms sensitivity and specificity:

        \n\nLR+  = sensitivity ÷ (1 – specificity)
        \nLR–  = (1 – sensitivity) ÷ specificity

        \n\nThe larger the LR+, the greater it pushes post-test probability upward towards certainty of disease.  A LR+ of 2 mildly moves up pretest
        probability to post-test probability.  An LR+ of 5 moves it a good deal more.  And an LR+ of 10 or more powerfully moves the posttest probability
        upward, all of which you can see with the LR calculator and pretest probability slider.  Conversely, the smaller the LR–, the more it pushes
        post-test probability towards certainty of the absence of disease.  An LR– of 0.5 modestly moves down suspicion of disease, whereas an LR– of
        0.2 moves it a good deal more, and an LR– 0.1 or less powerfully moves the posttest probability downward, which again can all nicely be seen by
        playing with numbers in the calculator.  Just like sensitivity and specificity, likelihood ratios are characteristics of a test itself and are
        prevalence-independent, which is to say they\'re unaffected by how common or rare the disease is.  PPV and NPV are prevalence-dependent.

        \n\nThere is an equation for how to derive posttest probability from pretest probability and likelihood ratio, but it is so dreadfully long that it
        won\'t read nicely in this small screen discussion, and it\'s not like you\'re gonna get out pencil and paper to do some calculations by hand (that\'s
        what this app is for).  If you really want the formula, you can find it at the Oxford Center for Evidence Based Medicine website cited in the app
        References tab (actually you\'ll find a set of formulas to convert pretest probability to pretest odds, then do the LR math on odds, then convert the
        posttest odds back to posttest probability).

        \n\nIf you would like to play with LR+ and LR- actual numbers from all across the breadth of medical practice, a nifty collection of LR\'s await
        you at the great site theNNT.com, and there is a direct link there in the References section of this app.</string>

</resources>
